<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Curriculum Isaac</string>

    <!-- __________________________________________DADES PERSONALS_________________________________________________-->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->

    <!--______________TITULS DE DADES______________-->
    <string name="Tnom">Name and surname: </string>
    <string name="TDNI">ID: </string>
    <string name="Tneixement">Birthday: </string>
    <string name="Tadresa">Address: </string>
    <string name="Ttelefon">Phone number: </string>
    <string name="Tmail">E-Mail: </string>
    <string name="Testat">Status: </string>

    <!--_________________DADES_____________________-->
    <string name="nom">Isaac Serrano Segura</string>
    <string name="DNI">47824289K</string>
    <string name="neixement">Pinell de Brai,\n april 19th, 1985</string>
    <string name="adresa">Av. Tarragona 19 3/3º,\n Vilafranca del Penedès,\n08720</string>
    <string name="telefon">628039336</string>
    <string name="mail">serranosegurai@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="estat">Married/without children</string>

    <!--___________________________________TITULS DE LES SECCIONS O FRAGMENTS______________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->
    <string name="index">Personal data</string>
    <string name="academic">Academic formation</string>
    <string name="profecional">Professional experience</string>
    <string name="coneixements">Knowledge learned</string>
    <string name="complementari">Complementary data</string>
    <string name="projectes">Personal Projects</string>
    <string name="descripcio">Description</string>

    <!--___________________________________TITULS DE LES SECCIONS O FRAGMENTS______________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->
    <string name="trucar">Call</string>
    <string name="imprimir">Print</string>
    <string name="configurar">Configuration</string>
    <string name="about">About this</string>
    <string name="sortir">Exit</string>

    <!--___________________________________CONTINGUT DE LA ACTVITAT INFORMACIÓ______________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->
    <string name="titulinfo">Curriculum Isaac (Beta)</string>
    <string name="contingutInfo">
        -App programmed by Isaac Serrano\n
        -Version 2.04, Updated 16/02/2023\n
        -Version in beta yet, it mean the program is end, now it is distributed because be tested with different
        machines, if is found some bug or bad view, please report the problem for be fixed.\n\n
        -Update information 01/02/2023.
    </string>

    <!--____________________________________________FRAGMENT ESTUDIS________________________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->

    <!--________________ESTUDIS____________________ -->
    <string name="eso">-ESO. Institut d\’Ensenyament Secundari i Idiomes Terra Alta. 1997/2002.</string>
    <string name="mitja">-Intermediate training cycle of machinist. IES de l\’Ebre. 2002/2004.</string>
    <string name="cnc">-Course of 609h control numeric computer. ASCAMM. 2004.</string>
    <string name="matrius">-Course of 590h design of dies.  ASCAMM. 2005.</string>
    <string name="superior1">-Higher training cycle of machinist production. IES Jaume Mimó. 2006/2007</string>
    <string name="superior2">-Higher training cycle of machinist production. IES de l\'Ebre. 2007/2008</string>
    <string name="plc">-Course of programmable logic controller. Euroinnova. 2009</string>
    <string name="angles">-English study ABA English 2014/2017</string>
    <string name="motlles">-Course of design of molds. ASCAMM 2017</string>
    <string name="cimatron">-Course of Cimatron E. Cimatech 2017</string>
    <string name="mecanografia">-Course of Typing. TypingStudy 2019</string>
    <string name="carrera">-Start to mechanical engineer. UNED 2019-In process</string>

    <!--________________CURIOSITATS____________________ -->

    <string name="curiosidad_cnc">-Like any professional career, it begins with training, and
        I would like do mention of the CNC studies in ASCAMM, there I was the best of the promotion, finishing the
         training with an advantage of a month and half of work compared to the second of the promotion.
    </string>
    <string name="curiosidad_superior">-The higher training cycle. there I taught two quarters
         of class to my classmates, the subject was CAD-CAM, and the teacher considered that my knowledge
         of the subject were better, so he proposed to me be the teacher.</string>


    <!--__________________________________________FRAGMENT PROFECIONAL______________________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->

    <!--________________EMPRESES____________________ -->
    <string name="goro">GORO. 2006/2010.</string>
    <string name="norelacio">Jobs without relation with engineering 2010/2012</string>
    <string name="canela">CANELA TOOLS. 2013/2014.</string>
    <string name="multivac">MULTIVAC. 2014/2016.</string>
    <string name="proto">PROTO-TECH. 2016.</string>
    <string name="molmat">MOLMAT. 2017/Present</string>

    <!--________________EXPLICACIO____________________ -->

    <string name="explic">Select experience to get information</string>

    <!--________________DESCRIPCIO____________________ -->

    <string name="dgoro">
        -GORO is a company that was closed in 2010 because the 2008 economic crisis.\n
        It was dedicated to the manufacture of gift products, decoration, jewelry, custom-made products…\n
        -My functions were very varied, because the type of product they made so varied, they also used
        many very different ways of production, also, and for my restlessness and involvement, I had an important
        evolution, from cleaning the place to managing the production.\n
        There I did manual work, turning, milling, polishing, welding with very different techniques, making molds in the
        lost wax, cutting dies, painting, CNC programming, designing work procedures, organizing the
        work, 3D design and much more.\n
        I also worked with many materials, industrial metals, many types of wood, precious metals, plastics…\n
        -I would like appreciate the trust they put me like the manager of production with just 23 years old,
        I only managed 8 workers, but it was a great learning for me.
        There I done productive studies and implemented production systems very different from those used until
        this moment, I designed, mechanized and assembled several automatic machines adapted to new systems of
        production, this did grow up the productivity more than 250%.
    </string>

    <string name="dnorelacio">
        -During this period of time, because of the area where I was born and living, it was practically impossible to work
        in the industry, so I decided to use some other of my skills to earn a living.
        So I began to teach guitar, private and schools, to teach chess, and to do
        tour guide on weekends, I even started composing an author album. \ n
        -At the end of 2012 I decided to go back to the industry, leaving my town, family and friends to go to
        look for work in Barcelona.
    </string>

    <string name="dcanela">
        -CANELA TOOLS is a company that manufactures cutting tools for turning machines, milling machines, etc.\n
        -My job was in technical office as a CNC programmer.\n
        -My function was to optimize the CNC programs of the manufacturing plant, the way to work was as if
        there not have program, about to stock, automatic work orders were created that had to enter the machine
        sooner. So, I reprogrammed the program optimizing code and time, I sent to machine
        taking responsibility of the programs to work correctly, as well as of the production line consisting of 10
        milling machines, and it cannot stop.\n
        -In this point I like to explain that all the milling machines had 5 axis, and it was programmed typing code for
        optimization of machine movements, using high-level parametric language. I like explain this because i was
         few years more in the industry, and I could watch that there are not many people with enough skills to do it.\n
        -I implemented a new and more efficient programming system, where I optimized the machining strategy guaranteeing
        the same quality with higher production. My work there was finished once all the programs were
        optimized.
    </string>

    <string name="dmultivac">
        -MULTIVAC is a company that manufactures machinery and molds for packaging.\n
        -I entered here as a CNC turning serial production machines, in just 2 months I was a preparer,
        In 6 months my preparations were the best of the plant, since I optimized the procedure and
        reprogram the programs making them much faster. So a year they moved me to the machining centers
        to make special pieces.\n
        -I applied standardized work systems for preparers, optimized work procedures,
        I implemented new programming systems, I even organized tests for tools, and cutting speeds.\n
        -Until my direct boss, the section manager, decided to promote only me, as the only programmer
        of turning for all the plant.\n
        -It was a great experience in a big multinational, with a plant of 150 workers, the biggest company that
        I have worked, but unfortunately, I decided to leave this place because I had a great job offer.
    </string>

    <string name="dproto">
        -PROTO-TECH is a company that manufacture prototypes for the automobile, parts
        for assembly of the first car, also machining a 1:1 scale car. They also make dies for the
        automotive industry, gadgets for production quality testing, and some other things.\n
        -I was hired as a CAD-CAM programmer in the technical office.\n
        -In this experience I did some interesting things, like working on giant CNC milling machines and
        use and program my first robot, it was a KUKA 6-axis articulated arm, nobody knew how it worked
        and they had it standing there, until I started it.\n
        -It be end, because I had disagreements with the work manager, I decided to leave the job.
    </string>

    <string name="dmolmat">
        -MOLMAT is a mold and die manufacturing company. The measures of the tools are medium and large, between 1 and 20 tons.
        The types of molds that work are: cast aluminum, thermosetting for pressure vulcanizing, injection of
        different types of plastic, bi-material rotary…\n
        -The job is as a mold designer. The basic functions are to design the molds,
        although part of my job is direct contact with the client to adapt the designs to their needs,
        Preliminary design, design and 3D drawing of the project, create documentation for manufacturing, contact
        suppliers, requests for quotes and purchases, manufacturing and assembly monitoring, testing monitoring
        and manage touch-ups.\n
        -As it cannot be of other way, I have implement news work procedures, like creating
        of an automatic bill of material generation system, the introduction of these bills to the
        management software automatically, creation of a new normative of build molds, normalization of parameterized 3Ds,
        creation of a purchase system based on pre-made email templates, software development, creation of
        mathematical calculations, program an IA for take decisions, motion simulations for designs, supplier evaluation…\n
        -I am searching a company bigger and where the resource not be a problem because I
        can implement all my knowledge in all environments.
    </string>

    <!--__________________________________________FRAGMENT CONEIXEMENTS______________________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->

    <!--________________TIPO____________________ -->
    <string name="cad">CAD</string>
    <string name="cam">CAM</string>
    <string name="fresa">Milling CNC</string>
    <string name="torn">Turning CNC</string>
    <string name="llenguatges">Software</string>
    <string name="programes">Office</string>
    <string name="idiomes">Languages</string>
    <string name="complementaries">More</string>

    <!--________________DADES____________________ -->
    <string name="Dcad">
        -Cimatron E\n
        -Inventor\n
        -Autocad\n
        -Catia\n
        -FreeCad
    </string>
    <string name="Dcam">
        -Cimatron E\n
        -Tebis\n
        -SprutCam\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="Dfresa">
        -Fagor\n
        -Siemens\n
        -Heidenhain\n
        -Fanuc
    </string>
    <string name="Dtorn">
        -Siemens\n
        -Fanuc\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="Dllenguatges">
        -Java\n
        -Android\n
        -SQL\n
        -Python\n
        -Prolog\n
        -More…
    </string>
    <string name="Dprogrames">
        -Office Environment\n
        -Google Environment\n
        -Open source software\n
        -OS Windows and Linux\n
    </string>
    <string name="Didiomes">
        -Catalan Nativ\n
        -Spanish Nativ\n
        -English B2 Intermediate\n

    </string>
    <string name="Dcomplementaries">
        -License B of driver\n
        -Guitar teacher\n
        -Martial arts\n
        -Draw in art school
    </string>

    <!--__________________________________________FRAGMENT PROJECTES______________________________________________ -->
    <!--***********************************************************************************************************-->

    <!--________________TIPO____________________ -->
    <string name="composicio">To compose music</string>
    <string name="aplicacio">Distributed Android APP</string>
    <string name="os">My Own Operating System</string>
    <string name="Maquina">Build a CNC machine</string>
    <string name="IA_gestio">Management program with AI</string>


    <!--________________DADES____________________ -->
    <string name="Dcomposicio">
        I have composed several songs in my life, I have never published any. But we could say that as a challenge to compose music, a challenge achieved,
         As a second challenge in this aspect, I would have to publish my compositions one day in the form of an album, or put them on the market for
         let a good interpreter make them public.
    </string>
    <string name="Daplicacio">
        I created an entire mobile app by myself.\n
         One day I had the problem of going to a job interview and I didn\'t have an updated curriculum, I have the curriculum in 3 languages,
         so updating the resume requires some work, besides, I had a folder on my computer with many updates in 3 languages.\n
         I also realized that every job interview I had to do had to print multiple copies of multiple pages with multiple languages,
         so I programmed this application for my resume.\n\n
         So I thought it would be a problem that many people would have. I started programming a generic app, bought hardware and set up my own server,
         I programmed a database with mysql, I started paying for a static ip and I posted the application on google play.
         Since I couldn\'t dedicate the time required to maintain an App with these characteristics, I decided to turn off the server and remove it.\n
         Project Done.

    </string>
    <string name="Dos">
        As in my work experience, both on a machine, as a programmer or designer, I realized that my main tool was always really
         a computer, I decided to learn more about the work tool that I used daily, so I began to investigate operating systems.\n
         With this concern and the obsession to make everything around me efficient, I decided to model the tool to do what I wanted.
         as I wanted.\n
         Thanks to the community of computer scientists and free software, I was able to get tools and programs already programmed, such as the linux kernel, a command terminal,
         and a package manager. From there I looked for packages already created, for basic functions such as the screen server that translates the data from the computer
         in screen data, or bluetooth, etc. I programmed my own desktop with a project I found that allows you to program it in python, I designed the
         behavior of windows that were ordered automatically according to a command given with the keyboard, I created menus, I put necessary information for me in the
         taskbar, like the price of some shares, or etherum next to the date and time to be informed, keyboard commands for faster work.\n
         In the end, I left the tool to my needs.\n
         I finished this project with the creation of the same operating system created, as installable and with a live USB, where with a USB I could start it in
         any computer, work with my operating system, settings and programs, and remove it leaving the computer in question as it was, without a trace.\n
         Finished project.
    </string>
    <string name="Dcnc">
        Working on a mill and lathe, I always imagined how to automate the work, how to add a part loader, how to change a part from one machine to another,
         add machine opening systems, automatic cleaning…\n
         Once I acquired the necessary knowledge of systems and software, I started with this project, mechanically designing a machine, assembling the hardware and programming.
         my own cnc, for this endowing the project with a large electronic and electrical part.
         Project in progress, working on the electronic part.
    </string>
    <string name="DIA">
        After acquiring a good knowledge of software, with android, python, java… I thought of going one step further in automation, I had imagined hundreds of times
         like programming a more personalized business management program, more efficient than what I had seen so far, I wanted something more automatic.\n
         For this I thought that the maximum automation is for the machines to learn to make the right decisions by themselves, and I delved into the exciting
         world of artificial intelligence, I realized that there are great advances in language and vision, but that decision making is related to the operation
         of a company with its tasks, it was not something widespread and required more knowledge, mathematics and algorithms.
         Right now I am developing a software project for a simulated mold company, which is where I have work experience, this project is more complex
         and expensive than the others, since I plan to teach the machines to design the molds, program the machines, organize the work, make budgets,
         contact suppliers, purchase materials… all automatically.\n
         I already have in my mind how I am going to do it, programmed part of the automatic design and part of the graphic interface, but I still have many hours of work and some of
         investigation, but I am fully qualified to carry it out, which already seems to me an achievement in itself.\n
         Project in development.
    </string>

</resources>
